Emmanuel! God is with us! My name is Salami D. And my name is Justin.
Viewers all over the world, we welcome you to today's episode of changing lives.
In this program, we are going to take you beyond the testimony, to the heart of how life was and how life is,
after an encounter with Jesus Christ through the Ministry of Prophet TB Joshua.
Yes, throughout human history we have seen that those who bless God in their trials will be blessed by God through their trials and
through this interview we will listen to people's real-life trials how they responded how they overcame through God
And why they are rejoicing in the Lord today, and why you too can. Yes and today,
we will have the pleasure of speaking with the Ipusu's.
Their experience of marriage had been a difficult one that would rub the faith of almost everyone.
Today, God's grace has united them with the unshakable peace and love.
Their incredible journey, along the highway of marriage, seemed to end even before it had begun.
Not knowing that the challenges and the trials they were going through in their
relationship were only the tip of the iceberg. Their story is an eye
opener to the real cause of why many marriages don't work out today;
ultimately leading to divorce and how the bitter taste of life's trouble can be replaced with the sweetness of God's grace.
So be blessed as you join us in Jesus name. So, here, with us on Changing Lives,
we have our special guests with us here, today:
Mr. And Mrs. Ipisu's. You're very welcome. How are you today?
Fantastic so we'll start off with Dosu Ipisu. Can you introduce yourself to us and share with us your wonderful testimony.
Thank you very much. My name is Dosu Ipisu.
My testimony is about, how I had lost affection for my husband and my experiences before and after my marriage.
And then tracing back, before I got marriage: what you hear about marriage is
more like something smooth, the bed of roses,
fun fair, you know. How many stories you hear about people getting married,
how they go for honeymoon and that was a dream for me as a young lady.
And then I met my husband, Mr Peter. He came along. We dated.
We had fun times up to the moment he said he wanted to marry me.
That was pic of hell in my life because
at that moment, he irritated me so much. I hated him more.
You know, he disgusted me. That's all I understood. At some point, I told him that why it must only be me.
What is so special about me. And I had a lot of psychological problems.
Thinking "why is this happening to me and all of that?''
And then I related to my parents and they told me that I should keep up with it. He's a good man.
Why not go a head and I told them : I don't have affection so how do I live with somebody that I don't love?
They keep telling me that love grows by the day. I told them let me back off from there now.
And hope that it comes on better.
But ,you know, it got more difficult.
Then just three days to my traditional marriage ,
I told him bluntly I'm not
going to marry him. Then my mom heard this she was like:'' oh my daughter, please,
you know, this is a dream for every mother to see her child get married.
And in my own case, I told her:'' for any reason whatsoever if you give him your consent;
then you're going in for the marriage".
So I related to him: you young man, I am not getting married to you.
I told him that bluntly and that's not easy to digest, you know! Three days to your marriage. It goes well.
He's going for the traditional marriage so, whether or not I come there it should be it fine,
get married if not he will walk away.
And so I fought that through until the day of our traditional marriage.
I finally got married against my will, anyway, I just did that out of play, jokes...
to just please my parents and
let peace be.
And so I felt okay, after the marriage
I will experience some peace, maybe, just like my father promised that love will come and will grow by the day.
We will get to do things that would get me into... but that never happened.
It will shock you to know that it got worse my dear.
Just seeing him, it would irritate me.
His sight's structure, I hated it. You with this pot-bellied where are you going too.
With stuff like that, and then he added it up with drinking.
He made it worse because I couldn't stand the odour.
He always stinks when he comes around. And in that kind of mood, he wants to crab jokes with me.
I never found anything funny. Even though he did his best. He would buy gifts when coming back home.
I didn't give into that kind, whether he gave me diamond, it didn't count. You know, I just wanted him to stay away.
Like this is a new marriage, you would like your husband around. He's not around you will miss him, you're
calling him. " Where are you? I didn't . In fact, it was fun for me when he was out. I had a great time when he
wasn't at home. So that went on
until, we start moving around, looking for solutions.
We felt everything wasn't just normal. We went to prayer houses,
we went, at his own side, he went to herbalists houses.
And then he came back telling me. Oh you are possessed.
They told me that" you're possessed with a spirit husband, and it's because you are possessed".
that's why, even at my workplace things are not moving or well for me. It's because you are possessed
that is why my car broke down, my business is not moving well.
And for your information, you will not have children.
More, so, reality will soon dawn on you. I'm quoting him now. "You know, he told me reality will soon dawn on you".
And then I taught myself, what am I doing in this place? Of what use am I in this place?
I am a woman who is not going to have kids. Your certificate will not get you anything.
I mean, I'm causing more trouble than good in this place, so I better excuse myself.
Being who he is, I knew that I couldn't live that marriage,
when he was around. I mean any time he was at home with me.
I could not live and so I took my time.
I was monitoring properly, and I knew exactly
when I was going to hit this.
You know. I just knew exactly when he was going to go out. How many hours he would have to spent?
wherever he went and it was on a Sunday. I had arranged with people out there, to come and pack my things.
When he went out I brought a vehicle. I packed each and everything. I mean
to the very last pin, I brought in to do my part, and that was my attention never to return.
What the am I coming back to do in this house?
When I'm not bringing any joy, I was not a fulfilled woman, not a satisfied woman.
So what was the reason for staying in the house?
So I packed with the intention of never coming back to the house.
I didn't give any room whatsoever for conversation. I mean that no chance for him to call me.
Just not occur to me cope I didn't give in at me if you called me if I when I left the house of
Up to two months, I didn't pick his calls.
You know, I have that capacity.
Just when I want to do it, I do it properly. He would call me, I saw those calls. Some times, I blocked him
from calling me, some times, I was just doing some favour by letting the phone ringing while I would pick.
He would send text messages. They are there in my phone. I never replied to one.
There wasn't any form of communication. That is because I didn't want any resolution.
And then my parents want to ship in. I told them enough is enough. I heard this before getting into the marriage,
and it cost me this pain. What do you think? Whatever advise you will give me what good will it do to me?
And so it looked like, I was getting to stubborn. No one could approach me. But I felt that, I should take my time
to seek for God's face. Then I would know the will of God for my own marriage.
I've gone to many churches of course. It's not like they didn't pray for me, of course they did the best they could.
But then I didn't get the expected results.
I didn't get the good goals, I yearned for.
I said; I will give one last try and that place is the Synagogue Church of All Nations.
Not because I was coming to look or to seek for prophet TB Joshua, is a mortal man like myself.
But I was coming to seek for that God in him, that sees in him mightily.
I said this to my husband. When finally I picked up my call. I told him for any reason whatsoever,
If we have to come back together again, then we have one last mission together,
which is to travel down to Synagogue Church of All Nations and by any chance we get there and I don't get
and I don't get delivered to the point where I will not experience changes myself, what will make my marriage
better. Then we should count ourselves divorced. I said if I am opportune to meet the man of God I would like
to find out from him: what is the will of God about this marriage? Because I remember, he said always
that in whatever situation, you are going through: God is still saying something and as a good
a Christian, we should always seek to know what is God's opinion about that situation. That was the only
reason why we had to come together, and travel together, and talk together.
We were doing all of that just for us to come to Synagogue. It wasn't because I love you. No, it wasn't
none of that. I knew what I wanted. All of that: hey , my love. There was just plastic makeup for us to come to SCOAN.
To God be the Glory.I think, I will simply say God's time is the best.
The choir, in Synagogue, sings: God's time is the best time, our time doesn't matter. I will simply say:
God met me this time that I came. Finally I was privileged to be prayed for by the man of God.
So, after you were married, it got to a point that you decided to separate. For how long were you separated,
before you decided that synagogue was the last bus stop. And you will seek the face of God at the
Synagogue Church of All Nations for pray.
In December, it will do three years in the marriage, and I left my husband on April 16. We came here.
It is about five months, I separated from the marriage.
and then when I came here, I was privileged to be touched by the man of God like I said and that touch!
Since that day! Actually, what I remembered, I manifested. I knew that something was speaking
through me. But I couldn't control it. I really didn't want to act out that way, but I couldn't control. It manifested.
Eventually, I got delivered, and we went back. My husband, too, was prayed for and after then , it was not
like before.
I didn't want him around completely.
I, now, miss him. When he just steps out like that, I will call him: hey boy, where are you? I will ask him to come.
back. What's he doing? I want to be involved in every step of the way. You know every step of the way .
Now, I care. Now, I have something to discuss with him. It wasn't like that before.
If he brought up a joke. I will tell him don't you have something better to say?
You know, I would be like
What's that?
How do I relate to these things you were saying? I never enjoyed his conversations and his jokes, his gifts.
How he wanted to buy me so many gifts. They were so much but , I never valued them.
But after the prayer, I needed to think at those things. I appreciated his efforts.
I acknowledged that he loved me. I felt that somebody cared for me.
I felt loved. I felt some satisfaction in me, even though,
there are still some hitches there of course. It's not a bed of roses.
It's life generally and that goes for everybody, every relationship. It's not always smooth.
You, always, have those patches along the way, but then ,you know after that prayer,
I saw those problems in a different light and then my approach to them was also different.
Not like before. It brought us
troubles, gave me headaches, caused me to worry:" what am I doing in this?".
I, now, realize that it's not him who is a problem. I'm sure this is happening in order homes, too.
You have those problems of quarreling, you don't ever agree . You are always arguing.
You always irritated. You don't love your husband. You don't admire him and maybe the feeling is normal. I am
here to tell them that it is not normal. There is nothing normal about it.
There's something wrong somewhere and your husband or your wife is not the problem, look deeper.
You would find
who is engineering all of this and fight that element, else, you'll be fighting the wrong battle and
you will never
be victorious until the end. It is almost happened to me.
It almost wrecked my marriage.
But now, I know how to approach it better in the light of God:
to see that it is the enemy who is putting up these acts in him.
He has just simply came to steal my joy and
make make me feel like he's not worth it? What am I doing with him? It's not him, it is the enemy who
does not want my happiness, who does not want us to enjoy our marriage, who does not want us to
live a Christ worthy life, because he knows that when he disturbs you and when your mind is not at rest,
when you are no more
happy within you because your heart is your prayer room,
as soon as he disturbs your heart, he gets your thinking, he gets your
You are ,now, doing some weird things that you know you supposed not be doing,
He knows that as soon as he does that
He has distorted your prayer life.
And so you can be able to fight back, rather you will see the man or the woman as the problem.
Now after that touch, I am
delivered and I have been taught how
to handle my problems in the light of God. Okay, so
looking back now, can you now say:
Maybe you've now regretted of doing things, your own way then?
Remember you did so many things. Sure, of course, I did.
You thought that you'll be home,yeah
But later on, you, now, thought you need to seek the face of God.
Looking back now.
I wouldn't say, I regret exactly, not because I'm a Christian, I would not have challenges
Or I will not have temptation, in fact
when those temptations come rather than to strengthening me
because Man of God says our faith
is tested upon the soil of
troubles trials and are flourished upon that soil and so far. A Christian that I thought I used to be,
God won't count that as a mistake
because I've come back to him to seek His face. If I had remain in
diverse or separation like I did
then I'll be condemned.
But I thank God for the Holy Spirit that also reminded me that it was not my place.
The devil is always trying to shift me away from my son-ship.
He's trying to shift me from my seat in God's presence, and so I will simply bless God for bringing me back
home. I call it back home because I
wonder what would have happened if I didn't come back and then again
I wonder how I would have grown if these trials did come because with this
like I said:
I've learned how to approach the problems better. Because I'm delivered now doesn't mean they will not
come again. God has simply told me on time that I should expect more, but then this is how best to
handle them. So that is wonderful
wisdom,
you've shared with us as well. We just want to take you back
what was your experience when Prophet TB. Joshua prayed for you and
had you ever received that kind of touch before in the past? As soon as prophet prayed for me
there was something different.
In fact, the first experience was that I had a very wonderful sleep.
I felt calm in my spirit. I felt some peace my spirit first. That was the first
experience that night.
And then I woke up the next morning, you know,
I mean before that deliverance.
I wake up in the morning, as soon as, I turn to see that I am still beside this man again. Oh, my God, what is this.
It's not happening again. I just hate his sight, just sighting alone.
It is just spoiled my day.
While I woke up before him that day. He was still sleeping and I sat back and I was looking at him.
How is it? Is this really me? It's you lying here. You didn't give up? Look at this man. There's more than this.
I was just sentenced to myself.
All I meant in the past,
I would possibly just slap him like this: hey wake up is
day break already, just take a bath and have your day at peace. series, so that I would have the house to myself.
Let me just have my space.
But that day when I woke up it was not like that. You know. I didn't want to disturb his sleep.
I was admiring him. Like: how are you? You are really a calmed man. You know, you could keep up with all
of this! I started appreciating from that moment.
That actually he's my husband, and I meant to love him and appreciate for whatever
is doing for me. so I felt that difference immediately. I can say that instant as possible that night
Now, we thank God Almighty for this
incredible deliverance and the changes that have taken place in your life. You can really see that it was that evil spirit
that was behind the
destruction of that marriage and so what I want to do now, I want to hear from Mr.
Peter now and hear your side of your testimony as well.
Thank you very much. My name is Peter Ipusu and I'm from Ebenue states. I'm a happy man today
because I've been through a lot.
I Knew my wife.
We stayed together,
lived in one room,
slept on one bed for two years I
I had to change her A,
Y,Z to what I wanted to served her, she agreed. At time, we
played together, and had a lot of romance.
One thing, we never did was, she told me young man, you want to marry me? I said: yes. So, she said
If truly I'm serious, I want to marry her, I should be calm.
But sometimes we could fight.
Normally we were best friends.
So when I decided to be serious with the relationship after two years. I met her in May 2012.
2012 we were together and 2013 by the end of it,
when I decided to marry her, that was the beginning of my troubles with my wife.
When I was not there, we could talk, we could smile on the phone. I could buy each other a card of 1,5 .
I would talk to her till the card are finished. As soon as she set her eyes on me,
there would be trouble. I was drinking but I was not in massive drinking.
So one of those days, I sat with a friend, we were discussing about marrying my wife but there is trouble.
For about those years that I've lived on earth, I've never ever in my life, visited a witch doctor.
Because I grow up from a Catholic home.
Eventually when I got there I
discovered that it was a spiritualist. I so I'm here. I can't go back. Let me get to know. I sat down
and they told me the troubles that were behind my marriage. That my wife was not meant to marry,
her past relationship is still going after her. And all sort of things. I should bring her for cleansing .
They would do some concoction and give her to take and then everything would be over.
So I came back to her
I discussed with her. She said over her dead body,
She will never visit any witch doctor for any reason.
But herself has suspected that something was wrong with her. How can a beautiful woman ,
every dream of a young girl is get married to somebody who loves her,
Here, I was showing her my love, it was time for marriage and things were not going right.
She had found a place where she was she was going for prayers.
So she said instead of going to the witch doctor we should visit the woman of God. We reached there
that woman of God said
let say
75 to 80% of the things I was told, so, I believed her.
I believed her so we're going there.
Best changes were not coming.
Changes were not coming. My wife could look at me in the face
When I decided I was going to marry her, she told me that I have no affection for you, you must go.
Because I had the knowledge of what the problem was and what this woman of God had told us, I never gave up.
Okay, just tell us
When you first met yeah for how long was the relationship going really well. For two years. For two years.
And then at what point, did you realize that it was a spiritual problem.
and it was not normal at what point. Two years and then
when I decided to marry her, when I proposed to her. I took out somewhere to propose to her, I brought a ring.
She said, guy, it is difficult for her to get this ring. She loves me, but she has no affection for me.
She loved me, she called me good names but she has no affection for me.
That woman of God told us a lot of things. There is one fundamental thing the woman said that kept me moving.
When she complained of no affection, the woman said if I
marry her affection will come.
So if we leave the prayer place and go to where we were running around,
She would agree.
Few days after she would say no.
All the events that were happening between us, I just new that it was not normal.
Let me just quickly shift in, there, at the point where he says, I agreed and and than I said no.
When we got to this woman, she is a prophetess
that I fellowship with. So when he said we should go to the herbalist, I said we should go to the woman
there was something she said to me. She said
if I don't get married to my husband then I'll never get married in my life.
And so I had all of this going through my mind: so if I don't get married to this man
I'm not going to get married.
Because when I went to her I was confused and I told her that please I want to know if this man is my husband,
that is exactly what took me in there
So when when we finally got there?
She told me that any man
I would bring to the church that was my husband and eventually I was taking my husband then not
as my husband, but because of the problems we had and he discovered it at the herbalist,
And I told him that
let seek the face of God which I had as an alternative, getting there,
and then she telling me that if I don't get married to this man. I was never going to get married.
That's also compounded my problem. You know to think of it
my flesh is saying no to this man, the same times the
Prophetess who sees better than I do, is telling me that if I don't get married to this man
I will never get married, so it compounded my problem, and made me act the way I did off
You know, I would say yesterday, say no tomorrow.
Like that. So three days to our traditional marriage, I was at her house.
About some time, we were her father, her mother, myself and her.
We were arranging how the next three days would be.
She told her mother in my presence,
if the mother agreed, the mother would go, to marry me and she walked out on me the father and mother.
Angrily
I took my car, went to town, had seven bottles of beer that
was about 11:00 p.m.. From Bokodos who have been to Makadi
that from bokodo to Makadi, I almost killed myself. I ran into a
ditch. I was drunk.
I tried to dodge a trailer, I ran into that pit and I stayed there up to 2 a.m.. I drove to Makadi.
6:30 in the morning ,a friend of mine
was very much close to us
knew that I have gone to arrange for the next three days, came to the house
And I told him the story. He told me there was a pastor we supposed to go see.
6:37 I was in that pastor's church.
The next thing, another friend of mine was calling me,
And then eventually, the guy drove to Makodi and I showed him where I was, in the church.
When he came and I saw my wife with him. This is not the woman who said that she will not come. What is she
doing here? I abandoned that pastor and came back home because my wife has said that we couldn't
get married. When we reach home, she said: boy, I won't do it again.
Ok! Tell us, Mr Peter, at that point in time, when your wife to be,
told you, she was no longer interested in marring you, three days to the wedding.
Actually, what was your reaction then. I wanted to make history.
Hmm, I wanted to make history. I wanted to make a history that a beautiful girl, a queen
you know,
queen like this,
a young man had come to marry her,
she refused to come out. I wanted to give her name.
So that other people would say off her: if you go to her she will run away. I also wanted to give him a name too.
So, I kept faith.
In fact it was
two days to our traditional marriage that
She agreed and came. We snapped pictures to give to people for souvenir, all that in only two days.
If you look at those pictures, they are very funny.
HELLISH MARRIAGE TURNED HEAVENLY
I am convinced, she has a tremendous respect for her father.
She has tremendous respect for her and she said he would
be disappointed in her because the parents, the younger ones, every body have accepted me in the house.
I didn't use charm on them. When I go there , they will hold me" good Peter".
The woman that I wanted to marry said now. Some how
we got married.
During our traditional marriage,
the whole, more than half of the church where we were going for prayers were at the back,
praying for us.
But a lot of things happened.
Within this time, we did some work and we had money somewhere.
The work that she was doing and I was doing,
she had some good money somewhere and the man who was owning us refused to pay that money.
So we started looking for where to borrow, and then, you know, God has a way of doing things.
It will be closed to where we would fail then God would open up a small way.
Okay, so you finally got married after your marriage? What were the challenges and issues you were facing?
Yeah!
If I began to say or discuss the challenges I faced
we will not leave here.
But the remarkable, I married this beautiful queen.
For three to four months, I had not met her as husband and wises. We were living in the room like toys.
To a point, I had to call a woman in my office to talk to her.
But,
there was no change.
She is very intelligent that I will no dispute she started
living a plastic life with me.
She wanted it, but you know
What you're not being from your heart
at a point where you are about to do it,
anger would come. Anger would set in and the feeling would disappear.
That led me into massive, massive intake of alcohol
I've married. I sat her down.
I had paid a bride price. I had told God at church that you, are my wife,
why can't I meet you as husband and wife ?
So I went into massive drinking. My office was supposed to start by 8:00 8:30. I would leave the house 7 o' clock.
The first place I would visit would be a beer parlor sometimes I ended up not going to the office.
I would stay, I would drink. Some days, I would come back, some days sometimes,
I would come back two days after, three days after
same clothes. I had taken
alcohol this part of the town, to morrow, I will drive the other part of the town, same clothes so those
people who saw me yesterday in those clothes would see me in this side. i they get there I'm in another part.
and then when I get home I
created an environment Where she could not ask me Where I was coming from.
Because I told her:" you had sent me away from the house, so you have no right to ask me where I'm coming
from". I come home and bath. I
developed a technique of moving up with a bag in my car so that I would have a problem of changing
my clothes. I would drink.
Sometimes I would sit in the beer parlor but I would not be drinking but I would not go home. I had that capacity
to drink from morning to night. Morning till the other day break.
I know joints that start by 10:00 p.m.
So when I finish the joints are close by 9:00 or 10:00. I moved to the one that start by 10:00 p.m.
to 6:00 a.m..
I invested my money into alcohol and
the devil has a way of doing things. It's the past I will say it. The devil has a way of doing things.
He will lead you to those friends that
will add to your predicaments. But you will thing in your own foolish way that you are doing good to yourself.
Because they will celebrate you.
However, they knew that if they called me, they would give me one, two bottles and I would offer a carton.
Because they knew that I was never tired and I said I wanted to go home.
So those are the kind of friends that the devil brought into my life at that time I
was into drinking. Even after my University in 2006-2007, I was very slim like you are.
When I got married I
didn't even give her the opportunity of
telling me something. There was no joy.
And that's why you find out a lot of young people,
today, you see them in beer parlors. Find out about their home, something is wrong.
It has happened to me. I has happened to me, and that had actually gave us troubles
I knew that she hated the test of alcohol, that was my best friend.
Alcohol became my best friend. When I came I want to hurt her. She would not ask me.
It came to a point if I got home, I would ask her:"what are you even doing in this house?
What are you doing in this house, pack your things and leave and I give me space.
You know and
I would said that I bless God today. I bless God today. She is a wonderful woman.
A woman who had married a man who you had no affection for,
then you lived in the room with that person for three years. It's not three days we're talking about.
We did these three years,
I could count
while I am sitting here, I can tell you how many times we smiled.
True smile with each other. I can tell you.
Three years.
Okay, Mr. Peter,
can I just ask you a quick question. Despite all the
difficulties you were passing through, you were facing what convinced
you not to give up on the marriage? Because even those in the witch craft told me that if my wife is fully delivered
I'm going to enjoy my home.
But the devil, actually,
blindfolded me not to seek God in the right way, not to seek to redeem my marriage in the right way.
I will visit one native doctor to the other, they would tell me the same thing.
I would visit the man of God who can give professes, they would tell me the same thing but the problem will remain.
The perfect way, made me moving was moving is God.
God wanted to do a new thing in our lives. God wanted to use me
as young couple to teach the world like we are teaching them now.
To let them know that it is better and best in Christ,
no matter the challenges.
We went through a lot to a point
I look at the girl. I also had a word" less privilege"
Not less privilege because you were from a poor home,
but
you are not to the standard of my own woman and I would get close to you and you would appreciate me.
I would look at the one that was more than her, I get close a good to her and she would appreciate me.
And then I knew that something was actually wrong in my home.
Today, I am celebrating her as a mother of my children that are coming.
This hat that she has,
my daughter is going to have part of it because it is not easy for a woman who had no affection for you
to endure for three years,
three years.
Whoever will tell you that go home manage. Ah !at the end of the day, it was two of us.
A child didn't come in these three years so nothing to divert the attention
from me. Can you tell us,
You mentioned, earlier, that you separated for five months, what led you to
finally seeking the face of God at the synagogue Church of All Nations
between you and your wife. Our God is a merciful God,
very merciful God.
We lived in Makodi, me and her alone in that house. When I would leave the house for three days I would
no come back. She would stay in the house alone.
So when she left I
decided to stay indoors, and I regretted every minute of what I did to her.
This small girl inside this house, all alone.
I remember some instance where I would come back, hoot at the gate. She would humbly come, 2: am.
and I would scold that at the turn of the road she supposed to know the sound of my car.
Within this time I sent her text messages that I regretted. She didn't respond to any of them.
We did speak to each other for 37 days. I was counting
I knew the circumstances that led to certain things, actually, told me that something was wrong.
On my wedding day I had accident. On my wedding day.
Nobody was driving the car. I parked the car, was talking to somebody and the car started moving.
I had an accident. When she parked out of my house.
And I wanted to find out where she was at her house. I had an accident.
So a lot of things happened that affected us were not normal.
That how I said let us seek the face of God
I appreciated the pastors that prayed for us. They did a wonderful job.
But I think God was preparing us to give us a testimony. Here we are today.
And so I have Emmanuetv in the house.
I have seen senior prophet TB Joshua, a humble man, reconciles homes.
Wonderful homes. There was a man
who was separated from his wife for 30 years or 35 years
He reconciled them. God was able to locate them.
It was when she left that all this start coming to me,
started coming to me.
And so she has one thing, anywhere is God, she would go. Any way the name of God is mentioned she would
go. We were discussing and she told me that she's tired of going into prayer houses.
The only place she would go, if it is synagogue she was ready.
That was when our finances
grounded. The devil knew that if we got here would be set free.
Every other person I discusses with: why do you need to go to synagogue, don't we have synagogue in Makadi.
Those pastors have been praying for us. My wife used to be unreasonable. I never give up.
So I did all I could .
I left pleasure to seek God and
eventually we got here.
When we got here something significant happened.
Something that, Oh God,I can't buy it .
I want to dance every minute. You won't understand the peace I have in my heart today.
I'm like, I'm already feeling like a billionaire because peace in my heart
When I came, I came with a stone in my heart
If you looked at me, you would know that I was not happy. To a point I was like I was going made.
I could wear bedroom slippers and
go outside the house something I never did before.
If your home is not settled , you are gone. You can never find peace.
How did you feel when you saw that your wife was receiving deliverance. Oh! my greatness!
You know, something happened,
all the people who prayed for my wife. She said amen. I said amen.
Troubles remained.
Immediately,
the man God, you know, I was lucky that I got the touch from the man of God before her.
So when I got that touch, I felt relief instantly. It's not magic.
It's not magic
It's not magic. I felt relief .so I was walking happily out
and then I heard a sound and when I turned to the television that was very close to me,
I saw my wife manifesting and I said thank you Jesus.
Immediately I saw that I said, thank you Jesus. I knew that the end had come.
The end of our troubles had come
So when she came out I pretended, I
pretended, she could not hold it
You know from
the deliverance point to the hotel where we were staying
She held my hand. I said Jesus. What is happening. Is this is real?
So we went home, she wanted us to pray, and she asked me to lead the prayer
I said: I'm so tired, she should pray.
She said a very short prayer. Thank you, Jesus. Thank you, Jesus. Thank you Jesus, and I said amen.
We all slept like babies.
She woke up. I didn't know that she woke up before me.
When I woke up, I saw her seating on the bed, she was looking at me.
Those eyes that I turned and I looked at her, that first day in bed, after the deliverance, touched my heart.
She said one thing that finished.
She said thank you for not giving up, and I said, thank you for enduring too.
That was the beginning. That was the day I wedded my wife.
Would ask yourselves that if it was before, she would, say smelly mouth, without approaching me.
She kissed me that morning. I said:" Jesus. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Wow."
That how it was. if it was before
smelly mouth, please excuse me.
She had kissed me that early morning kiss without brushing.
And I knew that God has finally visited my home.
God has finally visited my home.
It has been wonderful, and, I thank God that I never gave up. If I had missed this woman,
I don't think I would found another woman in this world better than who she is.
Thank you so much. You are welcome sir.
To God be the Glory. So now tell us, how is the marriage now after the deliverance?
If I start telling you, now, the experiences of one or two weeks, we will not live here.
Do you know, we're now praying together, we eat together. While walking on the road together.
When we were coming here, I didn't know that she was carrying a Roman soldier hair.
Only after the deliverance I admired her. I wanted to be sure of what has happened.
I would pretend and I leave the hotel go behind and stay there.
Five minutes, ten minutes, she would call me I want to go buy something. Please where are you? Come back!
But this come back now was more realistic than that of when it was plastic.
When it was plastic. Now, I am enjoying my home.
She is no longer abusing me that I have a potbelly. She will walk at my side and tell me that our stomach.
Before my ,now, it's our.
You know, it is so good.
If we didn't have any discussions at all, now, we can bring a topic from the Bible and discuss.
It is not like there are no challenges at all. They are there those that are not important.
If it was before, consciously now,I am trying to offend her to see her reaction. She's a wonderful a woman.
Thank God for this deliverance, we can really say that, it's a new marriage now. Yeah! But yourself, as well,
you had that problem of drinking alcohol. You said you could drink from morning to night after the prayer,
do you still have the urge to drink alcohol?After the prayers, the next day,
we were living our hotel to get something on the road, I saw people drinking and I said; see, look at those fools.
They're fooling themselves.
On top of that, one pulled his shirt. I said God! Jesus!
So this is what I was doing?
I hate the smell of alcohol now.
Those who are watching EmmanuelTV in my state and are watching me,
they will celebrate
because they know that
if me I can
come and tell the world that I am no longer drinking alcohol. Thousands of people will stop drinking alcohol.
I'm telling you.
Because, I know what the devil did. He spoiled my home completely. He spoiled my home completely.
So now, absolutely there is peace.
You know, you can't fake peace.
I can't fake it. There is peace.
You know, I, now, understand why people in Synagogue...
I'm not saying that those who prayed for us before didn't do well.
They did their part. God wanted us to get our deliverance to be where we are today.
We thank God Almighty for this radical transformation that has come in your marriage.
And we know our viewers are watching and we know they have been blessed by all
you have shared with them, and they also have question, they would like to ask you .
You will may be answer them and share more light on what you're saying.
We have a question from one of our viewers and
It says
My name is Calista from New Zealand and the question goes to you mr.. Peter it says
When crisis hits your marriage you ran to alcohol,
So like many do, so what did you learn from that and what advice can you give to others about that?
Yeah, what I learnt from there is that
when crisis hits you, run to God.
Okay. When you run to alcohol or to any of these earthly things you will destroy yourself and your soul.
I went through it, I destroyed myself,
my finances, my peace at home and all that. Finally, we ran to Christ, today, we are celebrating to Christ, today,
I'm celebrating because I have fully got Christ.
Nobody,
nobody should deceive you that when you have crisis run to alcohol, you will forget it.
For one minute you forget it, the next minute, it will come more. It rather increases your crisis.
Today, I have known that life without Christ is crisis.
Life with Christ is absolute peace,
absolute peace.
Okay, so we have
another question and it's for both of you. It's from Steve from Canada and
he says:
me and my partner have been dating for more than a year now.
And we are looking to tie the knot, what advice do you have for us?
Firstly, I will say:
Yet you tie the knots you should avail yourself for deliverance.
Buy that I mean,
probably you feel, you're alright,physically. there's nothing wrong with you, and of course the both of you
are enjoying yourself, but I'm just telling you this even gold passes through fire
to be what it is.
So you shouldn't think all is rose, all is okay. He's just
by the side of everything. Avail both of you for deliverance, first, before going into the marriage.
Yeah, and for those who are married, already, all of us, need deliverance,
all of us need deliverance. You may be fooling yourself thinking that mr. A is the problem mr. B is the problem
There's a spirit behind
every circumstances that happens
in our lives. Today, I can testify to that,
just to say your husband to be
is a problem, it's a problem or your wife. I wrongly accused my wife.
Even though all of us needed deliverance.
But that should not happen physically with them,
they rather seek God for deliverance.
Once you get delivered every other things come your way. Today, I'm enjoying it. I
I wish had taken this time years back.
But God's time said to be the best, so this is His time.
so I appreciate it. And
we were going for deliverance,
go for the deliverance in a life Spirit fit church.
If you are opportune come to synagogue.
Nobody should deceive you, nobody, this man is a man of God. I'm a practical example to that.
I can testify before the whole world today. He is a man who has never met me in his life before. He doesn't know
anything about us. I don't know anybody in synagogue.
But that touch
relieved my problem. I was coming to synagogue with my wife as a separated couple. Today, we kiss on the road.
She had said it from the beginning
that she never wanted to come back. But today, we are sharing our experiences as
joyful moments.
Find a Spirit fit church, if you can't come to synagogue. We went to so many places and they had prayed for us,
Some became very angry with us that we refused to hear the word of God.
The fact that they had delivered us that we didn't want to do the work we needed to do.
That touch ,from TB.Joshua,
is the Spirit fit church. We are living testimony. We go back and testify
Thank you very much for
sharing your time with us, here, on changing lives,
absolute, incredible advice and this is a new marriage, now, in Christ Jesus and
wonderful advice. We believe this testimony is going to touch
millions of marriages and people that are about to be married
around the world as well. Thank you very much. Thank you for having us. We bless God.
Hellish Marriage Turned Heavenly
When you hear about marriage, it is more like something smooth, the bed of roses , fun
fair. There are so many things in stories you hear about people getting married how they go for honeymoon
and that was the dream for me like a young lady.
In 2013 when I decided to married her
that was the beginning of my troubles with my wife. We had fun times up to the moments
when he wanted to marry me. At that point, in time, when your wife to be the
told you she was no longer interested in marrying you, three days to the wedding.
what actually was your reaction, then? I wanted to make history. Just three days to my traditional marriage,
I told him bluntly, I'm not going to marry you. Just seeing him irritated me,
his size structure, I hated it. I was like you with this belly pot where are you going too.
What was your experience when Prophet T.B. Joshua prayed for you? As soon as prophet pray for me
there was something different. I'am now missing him. Just like when he steps outside, I will be like; hey, boy,
where are you? We had this problem of quarreling, we didn't agree , we were always
arguing. You are always irritated, you don't love your husband, you don't admire him. You thing may be the
feeling is normal. I'm here to tell them that it is not normal. There is something wrong somewhere.
Well, what a wonderful
testimony in the life of mr. And mrs
IPUSU and we believe that there are many lessons that you learned from it.
You know that unfavorable situations are the great arguments that Satan uses to make children of God
to question their sonship, question their marriage and other areas of their life, and even question if what they
are doing is the will of God in their lives. The fact that you are a child of God does not eliminate
adversity such as the circumstances that happened in their marriage, but rather being a child of God
turns that adversity into an opportunity
for God to manifest His glory in that situation. Yes viewers,
we believe, you had seen in their experience that God can use any situation,
I mean, any foolish thing for his purpose and bring good out of evil. What seems like evil in the face of the painful
experience of chronic disagreements
disgust and hatred were eventually used by God to strengthen their determination and desire for Him.
Yes, what Satan meant for bad, God made it work for good. This testimony taught us that we need to rest in a
place that God has for us, so that His Grace can cover us. So if you find yourself in a situation that is contrary
to your expectations in Christ don't budge,
don't pull out, stay put and get used to that situation so that you can gain the necessary experience,
and maturity to handle the responsibilities in Christ. So viewers
whatever situation you are facing in your marriage should not break it,
rather strengthen it and your marriage can only be strengthened by you running to Jesus Christ for He is the Great
deliverer. Thank you very much for joining us on Changing Lives. My name is Justin and my name is
Salami D. Thank you, once again, for joining us on this program, Changing Lives and don't forget to join us on the next
Episode which will be coming very soon,
and also viewers,
We know you also have a testimony to share, you can send us your testimony through I.emmanuel.TV
We want to listen to your testimonies, because we believe your own testimony can also bless others.
Thank you once again. Thank you very much.
Hellish Marriage Turned Heavenly.
TT: ESTHER MWELWA 30/01/2019